First of all, thank you so much for being here with us. I want to ask you a few questions.
بادئ ذي بدء ، شكراً جزيلاً لوجودك معنا هنا.  أريد أن أسألك بعض الأسئلة.
First of all, tell me a little bit about the relationship you have with yourself?
بادئ ذي بدء ، أخبرني قليلاً عن علاقتك بنفسك؟
With myself before the accident?
مع نفسي قبل الحادث؟
Both.
كلاهما.
Both. Who was on social media? Who's using Facebook? Everyone.
كلاهما.  من كان على وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي؟ من يستخدم الفيسبوك؟  الجميع.
Have you ever put your relationship status complicated? My relationship with myself,
هل سبق لك أن جعلت وضع علاقتك معقدًا؟  كانت علاقتي بنفسي
before I was here was so complicated. It was all about people. It was never about me.
قبل أن أكون هنا معقدة للغاية. كان كل شيء عن الناس.  لم يكن عني ابدا
There was no me anywhere. You see people's pleaser. The person who just wants to make
لم يكن هناك لي في أي مكان.  ترى ما يرضي الناس.  الشخص الذي يريد فقط أن يجعل
everyone happy knowing that it's not worth it. You just keep doing it. Keep doing it. And yes,
الجميع سعداء مع العلم أن الأمر لا يستحق ذلك. أنت فقط تستمر في فعلها.  استمر في فعل ذلك.  ونعم ،
your relationship eventually with yourself becomes complicated.
تصبح علاقتك بنفسك معقدة في النهاية.
And then now, I don't know where there are people around me or not, but I me now. I'm more me now.
ثم الآن ، لا أعرف أين يوجد أشخاص من حولي أم لا ، لكنني أنا الآن.  أنا أكثر مني الآن.
That's so nice. What advice would you give to your younger self?
هذا لطيف جدا.  ما هي النصيحة التي تعطيها لنفسك الأصغر سنا؟
To my younger self? Interesting question! Well, I'll just make her sit next to me
إلى نفسي الأصغر؟  سؤال مهم! حسنًا ، سأجعلها تجلس
and very nicely, I'll tell her. Don't invest yourself in the wrong people. Because when you
بجواري ولطيفة جدًا ، سأخبرها.  لا تستثمر نفسك في الأشخاص الخطأ.  لأنه عندما
invest yourself in the wrong people, they break you into pieces, they torn you apart
تستثمر نفسك في الأشخاص الخطأ ، فإنهم يقسمونك إلى أجزاء ، ويمزقونك
in such a way that it takes years and years to get back together.
بطريقة تستغرق سنوات وسنوات للعودة معًا.
And also, I will tell her that while you are busy making amazing plans in your life,
وأيضًا ، سأخبرها أنه بينما أنت مشغول في وضع خطط مذهلة في حياتك ،
my dear, prepare yourself for worse. Because life is so unpredictable. Just be prepared.
يا عزيزي ، جهز نفسك للأسوأ.  لأن الحياة لا يمكن التنبؤ بها.  فقط كن مستعدا.
One of my philosophies in life is, is that there are three steps in order to repair your life.
إحدى فلسفاتي في الحياة هي أن هناك ثلاث خطوات لإصلاح حياتك.
First of all, is to change your personal story, then your daily rituals, and then
بادئ ذي بدء ، هو تغيير قصتك الشخصية ، ثم طقوسك اليومية ،
the people, you surround yourself. I believe so much in these. So tell me,
ثم الناس ، فأنت تحيط نفسك.  أنا أؤمن كثيرا بهؤلاء.  أخبرني ، ما
how important is to surround yourself with the right people?
مدى أهمية أن تحيط نفسك بالأشخاص المناسبين؟
Time is a beautiful teacher. It filters out the extras from your life, including people.
الوقت معلم جميل.  يقوم بتصفية الإضافات من حياتك ، بما في ذلك الأشخاص.
Being in the wheelchair in 12 years, I've had three categories of people.
كوني على كرسي متحرك منذ 12 عامًا ، كان لدي ثلاث فئات من الأشخاص.
Number one category is of the people who see you in the misery in pain and the backoff,
الفئة الأولى هي الأشخاص الذين يرونك في بؤس الألم والتراجع ،
they're like we are gone. We can't handle it. I respect them for their honesty.
وكأنهم ذهبنا.  لا يمكننا التعامل معها.  أنا أحترمهم على صدقهم.
Then there is another category of the people who are not there with you, but they just want
ثم هناك فئة أخرى من الأشخاص غير الموجودين معك ، لكنهم يريدون فقط
to cling on with you all the time. They're so weak, that they try to stay in your shadow.
التمسك بك طوال الوقت.  إنهم ضعفاء لدرجة أنهم يحاولون البقاء في ظلك.
Liberate yourself from those people, because they are toxic for you.
حرر نفسك من هؤلاء الناس ، لأنهم سيئون بالنسبة لك.
Don't let them cling on to you because they're not there to help you,
لا تدعهم يتشبثون بك لأنهم ليسوا هناك لمساعدتك ،
liberate them, liberate yourself, and then there is the third category. These beautiful people who
وتحريرهم ، وتحرير نفسك ، ومن ثم هناك الفئة الثالثة.  هؤلاء الأشخاص الجميلين الذين
are so selfless, that when they see you in pain, they stand next to you. They've got your back.
يتسمون بالنكران للذات ، لدرجة أنهم عندما يرونك تتألم ، يقفون بجانبك.  لقد حصلوا على ظهرك.
They don't share the limelight. They're just there for you.
لا يشاركون الأضواء. إنهم موجودون من أجلك فقط.
These are your people value them. So yes, there are three categories of people try
هؤلاء هم شعبك يقدرهم.  لذا نعم ، هناك ثلاث فئات من الناس تحاول
to surround yourself with those who are real, and you will feel real.
أن تحيط نفسك بأولئك الحقيقيين ، وستشعر أنك حقيقي.
What about jealousy?
ماذا عن الغيرة؟
What about? About jealousy.
ماذا عن؟
Jealousy? I pity them. I pity those who see their failure in your success. You know, these critics,
الغيرة؟  أنا أشفق عليهم.  أشفق على أولئك الذين يرون فشلهم في نجاحك.  كما تعلم ، هؤلاء النقاد
they were once dreamers. They just wanted to achieve something that today you have, but they
كانوا ذات يوم حالمين.  لقد أرادوا فقط تحقيق شيء ما لديك اليوم ، لكنهم
gave up and they started becoming jealous of you. Pray for them because they're in a lot of pain.
استسلموا وبدأوا يشعرون بالغيرة منك. صلي من أجلهم لأنهم يعانون من ألم شديد.
One of the things that I see usually when I do therapy, a lot of women, they prefer
من الأشياء التي أراها عادة عندما أقوم بالعلاج ، الكثير من النساء
to stay in a miserable relationship instead of get out. The fear of being alone is greater.
يفضلن البقاء في علاقة بائسة بدلاً من الخروج.  الخوف من أن تكون وحيدًا أكبر.
So would you give some advice to these women?
فهل تعطي بعض النصائح لهؤلاء النساء؟
We all tend to invest ourselves in relationships. And as I said,
كلنا نميل إلى استثمار أنفسنا في العلاقات.  وكما قلت ،
if you are doing something right, but the wrong person, nothing good will turn out,
إذا كنت تفعل شيئًا صحيحًا ، ولكن الشخص الخطأ ، فلن يظهر أي شيء جيد ،
and deep inside, we were quite intuitive. We know that it's not going anywhere.
وفي أعماقنا ، كنا حدسيًا تمامًا. نحن نعلم أنه لن يحدث أي شيء.
It's okay to be on your own. You are stronger than you think. Don't worry about that,
لا بأس أن تكون بمفردك.  انت اقوى مما تفكر.  لا تقلق بشأن ذلك
and wait for the right person. Let the right person come to you. There's no rush. Are you in
، وانتظر الشخص المناسب.  دع الشخص المناسب يأتي إليك.  ليس هناك اندفاع.  هل انت
a good relationship with yourself? Do you love your own company? If you're miserable alone,
على علاقة جيدة مع نفسك؟  هل تحب شركتك الخاصة؟  إذا كنت بائسة وحدك ،
I'm sorry, your partner will be miserable with you. So we need to understand
أنا آسف ، سيكون شريكك بائسًا معك.  لذلك نحن بحاجة إلى فهم
that we need to love our own company, only then people will love to enjoy our company too.
أننا بحاجة إلى حب شركتنا ، وعندها فقط سيحب الناس الاستمتاع بشركتنا أيضًا.
And don't rush. Wait for the right person. Because if it's meant to be, it will be.
ولا تتسرع.  انتظر الشخص المناسب. لأنه إذا كان من المفترض أن يكون ، فسيكون كذلك.
One of the things I usually say is that your relationships reflect your self relationships. So
من الأشياء التي أقولها عادة أن علاقاتك تعكس علاقاتك الذاتية.  لذا
the most important thing is to look within to fix the most important relationship that is
فإن أهم شيء هو النظر في الداخل لإصلاح أهم علاقة
the relationship you have with yourself. Muniba, I want to ask you, how do you want to be remembered?
وهي علاقتك مع نفسك.  منيبه اريد ان اسالك كيف تريدين ان نتذكر؟
Such a beautiful question.
هذا سؤال جميل.
I want to be remembered as an empath. Somebody who just didn't say that I feel your pain,
أريد أن أتذكر كإمباث. شخص ما لم يقل أنني أشعر بألمك ،
but I want people to see that when I say this I mean it. And as far as my life story is concerned,
لكني أريد أن يرى الناس ذلك عندما أقول هذا أعنيه.  وفيما يتعلق بقصة حياتي ،
I don't know how my story will end. Maybe it will never end,
لا أعرف كيف ستنتهي قصتي .  ربما لن تنتهي أبدًا ،
but yes, nowhere in my text, the world will ever read I gave up.
لكن نعم ، لن يقرأ العالم في أي مكان في نصي أبدًا.
Apart from art, What kept you going in life?
بصرف النظر عن الفن ، ما الذي جعلك تستمر في الحياة؟
I think all sorts of art kept me going. I love music. I used to sing. I still sing
أعتقد أن كل أنواع الفن جعلتني أستمر. احب الموسيقى.  اعتدت أن أغني.  ما زلت أغني
lullabies for my son, and just like painting art music is so therapeutic. So I love music.
التهويدات لابني ، ومثل الرسم ، فإن الموسيقى الفنية علاجية للغاية.  لذلك أنا أحب الموسيقى.
I don't know if the crowd would love that. If it's okay with you, would you mind sing
لا أعرف ما إذا كان الجمهور سيحب ذلك. إذا كان الأمر جيدًا معك ، فهل تمانع في غناء
something for us? Just to listen to your voice.
شيء لنا؟  فقط للاستماع إلى صوتك.
Have you watched Tangled? Tangled Rapunzel her journey how she comes out of confinement for the
هل شاهدت متشابكة؟  Tangled Rapunzel رحلتها كيف خرجت من الحبس
first time. She goes out and sees the world awaits her. You know what that song "I see the light"
لأول مرة.  تخرج وترى العالم ينتظرها.  أنت تعرف ما هي أغنية "أرى النور"
it reminds me of the times when I was bedridden,
التي تذكرني بالأوقات التي كنت طريح الفراش فيها ،
and I used to hear the kids playing outside. I couldn't see it. I used to hear thunderclap
وكنت أسمع الأطفال يلعبون في الخارج. لم أستطع رؤيته.  كنت أسمع قصف الرعد
I couldn't see the storms. I used to hear the rain falling on the ground. I couldn't see it,
لم أستطع رؤية العواصف.  كنت أسمع سقوط المطر على الأرض.  لم أستطع رؤيته ،
and I missed it. But when I sat in the wheelchair I stepped out went close to nature
وقد فاتني.  لكن عندما جلست على الكرسي المتحرك خرجت اقتربت من الطبيعة
everything's changed. So this beautiful song I see the light. Probably something I'd like to sing.
تغير كل شيء.  هذه الأغنية الجميلة أرى النور.  ربما شيء أود أن أغنيه.
"All those days watching from the windows
"كل تلك الأيام أشاهد من النوافذ
All those years outside looking in
كل تلك السنوات في الخارج أبحث في
All that time never even knowing
كل ذلك الوقت لا أعرف
Just how blind I've been
أبدًا كيف كنت أعمى
Now I'm here blinking in the starlight
الآن أنا هنا يومض في ضوء النجوم
Now I'm here suddenly I see
الآن أنا هنا فجأة أرى
Standing here it's oh so clear
الوقوف هنا إنه واضح جدًا
I'm where I'm meant to be
أنا في المكان الذي من المفترض أن
And at last, I see the light
أكون فيه ، وأخيرًا ، أرى
And it's like the fog has lifted
الضوء وكأن الضباب قد ارتفع
...the sky is new
... السماء
And it's warm and real and bright...
جديدة وهي دافئة وحقيقية ومشرقة ...
And the world has somehow shifted
وقد تغير العالم بطريقة
All at once, everything looks different.
ما في وقت واحد ، كل شيء يبدو مختلفًا.
Now that I see you.”
الآن بعد أن أراك ".
God bless you!
بارك الله فيك
Thank you so much. Antonio...
شكرا جزيلا انطونيو ...
Here comes the chief guest. He's so adorable! Oh my god!
هنا يأتي الضيف الرئيسي. انه جميل جدا يا إلهي
Oh, God bless you. Thank you so much.
يا إلهي بارك الله فيك شكرا جزيلا